Reed Graff

Entrepreneur | Engineer | Orator

CONTACT



972-730-2310



Rangergraff@gmail.com



Dallas, Texas



TheReedGraff.com

EDUCATION

Grade 9 - Present

Woodberry Forest Boarding School Woodberry Forest, Virginia

Grade 5 - 8

Cistercian Preparatory School Dallas, Texas

SKILLS

- Computer-Aided Design
- Computational Fluid Dynamics & Finite Element Analysis
- Data Visualization
- Web Design
- Logo Design
- Communication
- Leadership
- Political Analysis
- Oration

INTERESTS

Mechanical Engineering, Software Engineering, Data Analysis, Debate, Political analysis, Content Driven Case Studies, and Business.

PROFILE

Throughout my educational career, I have built a strong work ethic matched with consistently superior time management skills that have launched me to where I am today. I pride myself on my content-driven studies and projects, and I have a keen interest in Entrepreneurship, Engineering, and Oration.

Skills

World Languages: Latin (four years) and Spanish (three years).

Programming languages: HTML, CSS, JS, PHP, JSON, Python, Java, and C/C++
CAD, CFD, and FEA Related Softwares: Sketchup, AutoDesk AutoCAD, Siemens
NX, Ubuntu, OpenFoam, BlueCFD, Paraview, and Blender.

Courses

Community Service Hours (Highschool): ~60

SAT Score: X

ACT Score (Practice): 36 Math, 27 English

Most Recent GPA: X.XX (Unweighted on a 4.0 scale)

Freshman Year, 9th Grade

2019 - 2020

- Honors Physics
- Intro to Music
- Intro to Drama
- Algebra
- English 300
- History
- Spanish 1

Junior Year, 11th Grade

2021 - 2022 Courses:

.

Sophomore Year, 10th grade

2020 - 2021

- AutoCAD
- Intro to Visual Arts
- Intro to Bible
- English 400
- Geometry
- US History
- Chemistry
- Spanish 2
- ***AP Computer Science Principles

Senior Year, 12th Grade

2022 - 2023 Courses:

.

Sports | Activities

WFS Debate

Member (9 - 10)

Captain of Varsity Debate Team (11 - Present)

Debate is a formal discourse involving a large spread of topics. A typical case (one of two that one would write per tournament/resolution) that I would make would end up consisting of 80 pages of research, all compounded down into 3 arguments spanning 3 pages. Through debate I have acquired many skills that I am certain will aid me in the future. The communicative skills learned in debate truly can not be matched with any other activity.

- Competed in a selective State-Wide Debate Tournament as a Sophomore
- Achieved Fourth place in a regionals tournament as a Sophomore
- Completed several content-intensive case studies (all of which will be open-sourced on my website)

WFS Tech Crew

Member (No Student Leaders)

The WFS debate team is responsible for designing the architecture for the Tech Crew, I learned several skills, such as the programming that goes into being a lighting or sound designer.

Aided in design of Woodberry's reworking of Hamlet (Black Box Production)

WFS Skeet Team

Member (No Student Leaders)

The WFS skeet team engages in practicing the three main sports of shooting clay pigeons: skeet, 5 stand, and trap.

Outside of sports and activities, I often start the day by working out in our gym at 6:00 am.

Clubs

WFS Entrepreneurship Club (10 - Present)

Co-Founder, Head of Logistics / CTO

Our goal as a club is to educate students and members on entrepreneurial and business opportunities. We focus on teaching members how to manage a business, how to start a business from the ground up, how to work with a team, and ultimately how to be successful through teaching with on-hand experience. If you are interested in learning more I recommend visiting the simple website I made in HTML, CSS, and JS: https://wfs-e.herokuapp.com/.

 To explain this club's importance, Woodberry began to showcase our club to prospective students as a reason to come to Woodberry. Woodberry considered the club important enough to influence the future of their student base.

As a club we offer several activities including, but not limited to:

- Hands-on Business Practice
- Entrepreneurship Competitions
- Exclusive Conferences
- Student Hosted Case Studies

WFS Maker Club

Co-Founder, Leader (10 - Present)

My partner and I's mission was to help spread interest in STEM. Some of the activities we offered included:

- An introduction to the Arduino and Raspberry Pi library of products.
- Offered support with remote-controlled components, and autonomous components such as the FSI6 Transmitters and Ardupilot autonomous systems

Aided in attempting to acquire a laser cutter for Woodberry

WFS Ethics Bowl

Captain of the JV Ethics Bowl team (10 -11)

Captain of Varsity Ethics Bowl Team (11 - Present)

Ethics Bowl is a student-congress-style debate in which two teams of students debate cases. Through the ethics bowl, I gained valuable knowledge of leadership, reason, and communication. Unlike debate, Ethics Bowl is entirely unscripted, and the topics are typically about recent and relevant issues and how to solve them.

WFS Robotics Team

Head of Modeling (9 - Present)

Through the Robotics team, I have competed in head to head competition against neighboring schools in which we set out to program, design, and build a robot to complete a given set of tasks.

As a team, we competed in several regional First Tech Challenge tournaments.

WFS Computer Science

Member (10 - Present)

Leader (11 - Present)

The Computer Science Club focuses on teaching Python and the basic structure of code. The club also offered inside competitions in which members would face off against each other in who could write the fastest and most straightforward code.

- Python-based AI for the chrome dinosaur game.
- Python-based AI for Connect Four using a minmax algorithm.

WFS Investment Club

Member (9 - Present)

As a club, we managed over \$10,000 of our school's endowment and invested the money into several ETFs.

- Learned how to effectively allocate resources and prioritize interests.
- Learned how the market works
- I later plan on applying this knowledge to a Python Based Automated trading bot

WFS Science Olympiad Team

Member (No Student Leaders) (9 - Present)

"Founded in 1984, Science Olympiad is one of the premier science competitions in the nation, providing standards-based challenges to nearly 8,000 teams in all 50 states. We host 450 tournaments annually in-person and online and hold professional development workshops that showcase innovative STEM content."

Aided in projects set to compete, but due to Covid and conflicting schedules, I was never able to fully participate.

WCF, Woodberry Christian Fellowship

Member (No Student Leaders) (10 - Present)

The Woodberry Christian Fellowship teaches students about The Bible and exposes members of our community to the ideology and perspective that the Christian faith has on certain topics.

Meetings are typically very open, and you get what you put into it.

Coffee Society

Member (10 - Present)***

RC Club

Member (10 - Present)***

Gay Straight Alliance

Member (10 - Present)

Noteworthy Businesses and Projects

PET Earth

Founder, CFO, CTO, CEO (10 - Present)

PPPET (PolyPropylene, PolyEtheleneTrithalate) Earth. Repurposes polypropylene, and makes 3d printable filament.

5 Active Full Stack HTML Based Applications

"Hot Takes" Social Media

Founder (10 - Present)

Repurposing of Covid-19 Masks

Kingpin's Cards

Founder (10 - Present)

Extracurricular Courses and Studies

Harvard Summer Debate Council (Public Forum)

Cambridge, MA (Summer in between 10 - 11)

The Harvard Debate Council is a rigorous two-week program taking a deep dive into political analysis in a rigorous ivy league environment in which students are faced off against the best of the best.

- Content-driven case studies
- Communication

Scouts of America

Dallas, Texas

Not only was I a member of the Scouts, but my accomplishments in the scouts can also stand as a Testimony to my drive and hard work while enrolled.

- Life Scout (Soon to be Eagle)
- Order of The Arrow
- 1 bronze, and 1 silver palm (I acquired 20 additional merit badges throughout the course of my enrollment)
- Philmont Scout Ranch: travelled 114 miles in 12 days with ~60 pound packs.

Free Code Camp Responsive Web Design (~300 Hours*) (In the process of being completed, I am not yet done)

Self Taught Course Online

Mission: "To help people learn to code for free. We accomplish this by creating thousands of videos, articles, and interactive coding lessons - all freely available to the public. We also have thousands of freeCodeCamp study groups around the world." The

course I am taking teaches the programming languages that are widely used by developers around the world to build beautiful and reactive websites.

Several Youtube Courses covering CAD, CFD, FEA, Ubuntu, and much more.